Guide to the Monroe Wheeler Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Financial Papers, 1920-88; Series IV; 11.13; (27 boxes)
  Series IV, Financial Papers, is arranged alphabetically and chronologically.
  - LABELED FOLDERS
    - "Ask Jack Balaam", 1982-83 (Box 139, Folder 1663)
    - "Borden" [re: taxes], 1986-87, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 1664)
    - "Capital gains and losses-1971" (Box 139, Folder 1665)
    - "Chase deposit slips", n.d. (Box 139, Folder 1666)
    - "Finance", 1971, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 1667)
    - "Finance-current", 1972-75, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 1668)
    - "Investments", 1965-84, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 1669)
    - "IRS 1980, 1978, 1972", 1972-81 (Box 139, Folder 1670)
    - "Monroe Wheeler, Tax Substantiations", 1954-66, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 1671)
    - "M.W. - Bills and other business papers", 1947-50, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 1672)
    - "M.W. - Bills & Receipts, 1950-51" (Box 139, Folder 1673)
    - "M.W. - Expenditures in Europe 1951", 1951, n.d. (Box 139, Folder 1674)
    - "NY State tax deductions", 1955-76 (Box 139, Folder 1675)
    - "Old tax returns", 1942-49 (Box 139, Folder 1676)
    - "Paid bills", ca. 1940-51 (Box 140, Folder 1677)
    - "Paid-up life insurance policy", 1928-78 (Box 140, Folder 1678)
    - "San Diego Imperial Corp", 1962 (Box 140, Folder 1679)
    - Seamen's Bank, 1983-84 (Box 140, Folder 1680)
    - "Tri-Continental dividend forms", 1975 (Box 140, Folder 1681)
    - "Various bills, etc. (from 410 May 55)", ca. 1951-55 (Box 140, Folder 1682)
    - "Xerox" [Investment information], 1970 (Box 140, Folder 1683)
  - CHECKBOOK LEDGERS
    - Ledger, 1938-41 (Box 141, Folder 1684)
    - Checkbook ledger, 1946-47 (Box 141, Folder 1685)
    - Checkbook ledger, 1947-48 (Box 141, Folder 1686)
    - Ledger, 1950 (Box 141, Folder 1687)
    - Checkbook ledger, 1952-53 (Box 141, Folder 1688)
    - Checkbook ledger, 1953-54 (Box 142, Folder 1689)
    - Checkbook ledger, 1954-55 (Box 143, Folder 1690)
    - Checkbook ledger, 1955 (Box 143, Folder 1691)
    - Checkbook ledger, 1956 (Box 143, Folder 1692)
    - Checkbook ledger, 1956-57 (Box 144, Folder 1693)
    - Checkbook ledger, 1957-58 (Box 144, Folder 1694)
    - Checkbook ledger, 1958 (Box 144, Folder 1695)
    - Checkbook ledger, 1959 (Box 145, Folder 1696)
    - Checkbook ledger, 1960 (Box 145, Folder 1697)
    - Checkbook ledger, 1966 (Box 145, Folder 1698)
    - Checkbook ledger, 1966 (Box 146, Folder 1699)
    - Checkbook ledger, 1968 (Box 146, Folder 1700)
    - Checkbook ledger, 1970-71 (Box 146, Folder 1701)
    - Checkbook ledger, 1975 (Box 147, Folder 1702)
    - Checkbook ledger, 1979 (Box 147, Folder 1703)
    - Checkbook ledger, 1979 (Box 147, Folder 1704)
    - Checkbook ledger, 1981 (Box 147, Folder 1705)
    - Checkbook ledger, 1986 (Box 147, Folder 1706)
    - Checkbook ledger, 1987 (Box 147, Folder 1707)
  - GENERAL FINANCIAL PAPERS
    - Cancelled checks, 1920 (Box 148, Folder 1708)
    - Cancelled checks, 1933 (Box 148, Folder 1709)
    - Cancelled checks, 1934 (Box 148, Folder 1710)
    - Receipts, 1934 (Box 148, Folder 1711)
    - Cancelled checks, 1935 (Box 148, Folder 1712)
    - Cancelled checks, 1936 (Box 148, Folder 1713)
    - Cancelled checks, 1939 (Box 148, Folder 1714-1715)
    - Receipts, 1939 (Box 148, Folder 1716)
    - Tax materials, 1939 (Box 148, Folder 1717)
    - Cancelled checks, 1940 (Box 148, Folder 1718)
    - Receipts, 1940 (Box 148, Folder 1719)
    - Cancelled checks, 1941 (Box 148, Folder 1720)
    - Cancelled checks, 1942 (Box 148, Folder 1721-1722)
    - Cancelled checks, 1943 (Box 148, Folder 1723)
    - Cancelled checks, 1944 (Box 148, Folder 1724)
    - Receipts, 1944 (Box 148, Folder 1725)
    - Cancelled checks, 1945 (Box 148, Folder 1726)
    - Receipts, 1945 (Box 148, Folder 1727)
    - Cancelled checks, 1946 (Box 148, Folder 1728)
    - Receipts, 1946 (Box 149, Folder 1729)
    - Tax materials, 1946 (Box 149, Folder 1730)
    - Cancelled checks, 1947 (Box 149, Folder 1731)
    - Receipts, 1947 (Box 149, Folder 1732-1733)
    - Tax materials, 1947 (Box 149, Folder 1734)
    - Cancelled checks, 1948 (Box 149, Folder 1735-1736)
    - Receipts, 1948 (Box 149, Folder 1737-1738)
    - Tax materials, 1948 (Box 149, Folder 1739)
    - Cancelled checks, 1949 (Box 149, Folder 1740)
    - Receipts, 1949 (Box 149, Folder 1741)
    - Tax materials, 1949 (Box 150, Folder 1742)
    - Receipts, 1950 (Box 150, Folder 1743)
    - Tax materials, 1950 (Box 150, Folder 1744)
    - Cancelled checks, 1951 (Box 150, Folder 1745)
    - Receipts, 1951 (Box 150, Folder 1746)
    - Tax materials, 1951 (Box 150, Folder 1747)
    - Cancelled checks, 1952 (Box 150, Folder 1748)
    - Receipts, 1952 (Box 150, Folder 1749)
    - Tax materials, 1952 (Box 150, Folder 1750)
    - Cancelled checks, 1953 (Box 151, Folder 1751)
    - Receipts, 1953 (Box 151, Folder 1752)
    - Tax materials, 1953 (Box 151, Folder 1753)
    - Receipts, 1954 (Box 151, Folder 1754-1755)
    - Tax materials, 1954 (Box 151, Folder 1756)
    - Cancelled checks, 1955 (Box 151, Folder 1757)
    - Receipts, 1955 (Box 151, Folder 1758)
    - Tax materials, 1955 (Box 151, Folder 1759)
    - Receipts, 1956 (Box 151, Folder 1760-1761)
    - Tax materials, 1956 (Box 152, Folder 1762)
    - Receipts, 1957 (Box 152, Folder 1763)
    - Tax materials, 1957 (Box 152, Folder 1764)
    - Receipts, 1958 (Box 152, Folder 1765)
    - Investment information, 1958 (Box 152, Folder 1766)
    - Tax materials, 1958 (Box 152, Folder 1767-1768)
    - Cancelled, 1959 (Box 152, Folder 1769)
    - Receipts, 1959 (Box 152, Folder 1770)
    - Tax materials, 1959 (Box 152, Folder 1771-1774)
    - Cancelled checks, 1960 (Box 153, Folder 1775)
    - Receipts, 1960 (Box 153, Folder 1776)
    - Tax materials, 1960 (Box 153, Folder 1777-1781)
    - Cancelled checks, 1961 (Box 153, Folder 1782)
    - Investment information, 1961 (Box 153, Folder 1783)
    - Receipts, 1961 (Box 153, Folder 1784)
    - Tax materials, 1961 (Box 153, Folder 1785)
    - Cancelled checks, 1962 (Box 153, Folder 1786)
    - Investment information, 1962 (Box 153, Folder 1787)
    - Receipts, 1962 (Box 153, Folder 1788)
    - Tax materials, 1962 (Box 153, Folder 1789)
    - Cancelled checks, 1963 (Box 153, Folder 1790)
    - Receipts, 1963 (Box 153, Folder 1791)
    - Cancelled checks, 1964 (Box 153, Folder 1792)
    - Investment information, 1964 (Box 153, Folder 1793)
    - Receipts, 1964 (Box 153, Folder 1794)
    - Tax materials, 1964 (Box 153, Folder 1795)
    - Cancelled checks, 1965 (Box 153, Folder 1796)
    - Investment information, 1965 (Box 153, Folder 1797-1798)
    - Receipts, 1965 (Box 153, Folder 1799)
    - Investment information, 1966 (Box 153, Folder 1800)
    - Receipts, 1966 (Box 153, Folder 1801)
    - Tax materials, 1966 (Box 153, Folder 1802)
    - Tax materials, 1966 (Box 154, Folder 1803-1804)
    - Cancelled checks, 1967 (Box 154, Folder 1805)
    - Investment information, 1967 (Box 154, Folder 1806)
    - Receipts, 1967 (Box 154, Folder 1807)
    - Tax materials, 1967 (Box 154, Folder 1808)
    - Checking account information, 1968 (Box 154, Folder 1809)
    - Investment information, 1968 (Box 154, Folder 1810)
    - Receipts, 1968 (Box 154, Folder 1811)
    - Tax materials, 1968 (Box 154, Folder 1812-1814)
    - Checking account information, 1969 (Box 154, Folder 1815)
    - Investment information, 1969 (Box 154, Folder 1816)
    - Receipts, 1969 (Box 155, Folder 1817)
    - Tax materials, 1969 (Box 155, Folder 1818-1820)
    - Checking account information, 1970 (Box 155, Folder 1821)
    - Investment information, 1970 (Box 155, Folder 1822)
    - Receipts, 1970 (Box 155, Folder 1823-1824)
    - Tax materials, 1970 (Box 155, Folder 1825)
    - Checking account information, 1971 (Box 155, Folder 1826)
    - Investment information, 1971 (Box 155, Folder 1827)
    - Receipts, 1971 (Box 155, Folder 1828)
    - Tax materials, 1971 (Box 155, Folder 1829)
    - Checking account information, 1972 (Box 155, Folder 1830)
    - Investment information, 1972 (Box 156, Folder 1831-1832)
    - Receipts, 1972 (Box 156, Folder 1833)
    - Tax materials, 1972 (Box 156, Folder 1834-1836)
    - Checking account information, 1973 (Box 156, Folder 1837)
    - Investment information, 1973 (Box 156, Folder 1838)
    - Receipts, 1973 (Box 156, Folder 1839)
    - Tax materials, 1973 (Box 156, Folder 1840)
    - Checking account information, 1974 (Box 156, Folder 1841)
    - Investment information, 1974 (Box 156, Folder 1842)
    - Receipts, 1974 (Box 156, Folder 1843)
    - Tax materials, 1974 (Box 156, Folder 1844-1846)
    - Checking account information, 1975 (Box 156, Folder 1847)
    - Checking account information, 1975 (Box 157, Folder 1848-1849)
    - Investment information, 1975 (Box 157, Folder 1850-1852)
    - Receipts, 1975 (Box 157, Folder 1853)
    - Tax materials, 1975 (Box 157, Folder 1854)
    - Checking account information, 1976 (Box 157, Folder 1855-1856)
    - Investment information, 1976 (Box 157, Folder 1857-1858)
    - Receipts, 1976 (Box 158, Folder 1859)
    - Tax materials, 1976 (Box 158, Folder 1860)
    - Checking account information, 1977 (Box 158, Folder 1861)
    - Investment information, 1977 (Box 158, Folder 1862-1863)
    - Receipts, 1977 (Box 158, Folder 1864)
    - Tax materials, 1977 (Box 158, Folder 1865)
    - Checking account information, 1978 (Box 158, Folder 1866)
    - Investment information, 1978 (Box 158, Folder 1867)
    - Receipts, 1978 (Box 158, Folder 1868)
    - Tax materials, 1978 (Box 158, Folder 1869)
    - Checking account information, 1979 (Box 158, Folder 1870)
    - Investment information, 1979 (Box 158, Folder 1871)
    - Investment information, 1979 (Box 159, Folder 1872-1873)
    - Receipts, 1979 (Box 159, Folder 1874-1875)
    - Tax materials, 1979 (Box 159, Folder 1876-1881)
    - Tax materials, 1979 (Box 160, Folder 1882-1883)
    - Checking account information, 1980 (Box 160, Folder 1884-1885)
    - Investment information, 1980 (Box 160, Folder 1886-1887)
    - Receipts, 1980 (Box 160, Folder 1888)
    - Tax materials, 1980 (Box 160, Folder 1889)
    - Checking account information, 1981 (Box 160, Folder 1890)
    - Investment information, 1981 (Box 160, Folder 1891-1892)
    - Receipts, 1981 (Box 160, Folder 1893)
    - Tax materials, 1981 (Box 160, Folder 1894)
    - Tax materials, 1981 (Box 161, Folder 1895-1901)
    - Checking account information, 1982 (Box 161, Folder 1902)
    - Investment information, 1982 (Box 161, Folder 1903-1904)
    - Receipts, 1982 (Box 161, Folder 1905)
    - Tax materials, 1982 (Box 162, Folder 1906-1907)
    - Checking account information, 1983 (Box 162, Folder 1908)
    - Investment information, 1983 (Box 162, Folder 1909-1910)
    - Receipts, 1983 (Box 162, Folder 1911)
    - Tax materials, 1983 (Box 162, Folder 1912)
    - Checking account information, 1984 (Box 162, Folder 1913-1914)
    - Investment information, 1984 (Box 162, Folder 1915-1916)
    - Receipts, 1984 (Box 162, Folder 1917)
    - Receipts, 1984 (Box 163, Folder 1918)
    - Tax materials, 1984 (Box 163, Folder 1919)
    - Checking account information, 1985 (Box 163, Folder 1920)
    - Investment information, 1985 (Box 163, Folder 1921)
    - Receipts, 1985 (Box 163, Folder 1922)
    - Tax materials, 1985 (Box 163, Folder 1923-1925)
    - Checking account information, 1986 (Box 163, Folder 1926-1928)
    - Investment information, 1986 (Box 164, Folder 1929)
    - Receipts, 1986 (Box 164, Folder 1930)
    - Tax materials, 1986 (Box 164, Folder 1931)
    - Checking account information, 1987 (Box 164, Folder 1932-1933)
    - Investment information, 1987 (Box 164, Folder 1934-1935)
    - Receipts, 1987 (Box 164, Folder 1936-1938)
    - Tax materials, 1987 (Box 164, Folder 1939-1940)
    - Checking account information, 1988 (Box 164, Folder 1941)
    - Receipts, 1988 (Box 164, Folder 1942)
    - Checking account information, n.d. (Box 164, Folder 1943-1944)
    - Investment information, n.d. (Box 165, Folder 1945-1949)
    - Receipts, n.d. (Box 165, Folder 1950-1952)
    - Tax materials, n.d. (Box 165, Folder 1953)
- Photographs, 1931-81, n.d.; Series V; 0.42; (1 box)
  Series V, Photographs, consists of seven subseries, which are arranged alphabetically and chronologically.
  - GLENWAY WESCOTT
    - Portraits, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 1954)
      one photograph by GPL
    - GW and others (Box 166, Folder 1955)
    - GW and siblings, 1976 (Box 166, Folder 1956)
  - MONROE WHEELER
    - Portraits, 1979, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 1957)
    - MW and others in India (Box 166, Folder 1958)
  - OTHER PEOPLE
    - Douglas, Michael, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 1959)
    - Evans, Newton & Helen Parker Evans, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 1960)
    - Hilton, Joseph, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 1961)
    - Lynes, Adelaide, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 1962)
      - by Charles Howard, n.d.
    - Moore, Marianne, at Mt. Holyoke with MW, 1950 Jun (Box 166, Folder 1963)
    - Mortimer, Raymond, with Mario Amaya, 1964 (Box 166, Folder 1964)
    - Porter, Katherine Anne, 1931-47, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 1965)
      includes shots with GPL and Randy Jack and with MW
    - "Grupo de Teatro": Bogota, Colombia, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 1966)
    - Unidentified, 1968-81, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 1967)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS IN SERIES
    - Social events and gatherings
      - GW, MW, Anatole Pohorilenko and others, 1978 Apr (Box 166, Folder 1968)
      - GW, MW and others (Box 166, Folder 1969)
    - Travel, foreign
      - Chile (International Council of MOMA), 1968 May 12 (Box 166, Folder 1970)
  - ART PHOTOGRAPHY
    - Lynes, George Platt
      - Three postcard fashion test prints, commercial postcard reproduction of self-portrait, and description sheets for photographs (not included) (Box 166, Folder 1971-1972)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS OF ARTISTS' WORKS
    - Artworks owned by MW & GW, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 1973-1976)
    - Atget, Eugene, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 1977)
    - Cadmus, Paul, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 1978)
      [sketch titled: "Barbara and Lloyd in their midlife"]
    - Claussen, Hermann, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 1979)
    - French paintings, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 1980)
    - Installation at the Bienal do Museo de Arte Moderno de Sao Paulo, 1953-54 (Box 166, Folder 1981)
    - Perlin, Bernard, 1948 Dec 2 (Box 166, Folder 1982)
    - Tchelitchew, Pavel, 1935, 1964, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 1983-1984)
    - Wiemiler, Ignatz, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 1985)
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 1986)
  - VARIOUS SUBJECTS
    - Animals, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 1987)
    - Buildings, 1960, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 1988)
    - Foreign scenes, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 1989)
    - Interiors, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 1990)
    - Villefranche-sur-mer, France, n.d. (Box 166, Folder 1991)
- Graphic Items, ca. 1947-80s; Series VI; 5; (9 boxes)
  Series VI, Graphic Items, consists of three subseries, which are arranged alphabetically.
  - ARTWORK ORIGINALS
    - Albers, Josef: plate from The Interaction of Color, 1962 (Box 167, Folder 1992)
    - Blayton, ---, inkprint, 1975 (Box 167, Folder 1993)
    - Cadmus, Paul, print of George Cruikshank etching, n.d. (Box 167, Folder 1994)
    - Calder, Alexander, proof of designs for Christmas cards, 1947, n.d. (Box 167, Folder 1995)
    - Huppler, Dudley, printed cards with assorted sketches, n.d. (Box 167, Folder 1996)
    - Kemble, ---, inkprint: trees, 1975 (Box 167, Folder 1997)
    - Miller, Christian William, pencil sketch: nude male, 1951 (Box 167, Folder 1998)
    - [Mithila women], drawing, women (Box 167, Folder 1999)
    - Reder, ---, watercolor drawing: figure with table, 1960 Mar (Box 167, Folder 2000)
    - [Roturdas?], Edward J., ink sketch: Monroe Wheeler, n.d. (Box 167, Folder 2001)
    - Unidentified, colored computer print: MW & GW, n.d. (Box 167, Folder 2002)
    - Unidentified, various media, n.d. (Box 167, Folder 2003-2006)
  - ART REPRODUCTIONS
    - Cocteau, Jean, sketches of sailors, photocopy, n.d. (Box 167, Folder 2007)
    - Thomas, Dylan, "Queen Edith Sitwell and Princess Marianne Moore on their first meeting", sketch, photocopy, 1952 (Box 167, Folder 2008)
    - Commercial reproductions of artworks, n.d. (Box 167, Folder 2009)
    - Portfolio of reproductions of paintings, n.d. (Box 167, Folder 2010-2013)
  - OTHER ITEMS
    - Bookmarks and letters (Box 168, Folder 2014)
    - Commercial advertising card, n.d. (Box 168, Folder 2015)
    - Images clipped from publications, ca. 1950s-80s (Box 168, Folder 2016-2018)
    - Marble paper samples, n.d. (Box 168, Folder 2019)
    - Postage stamps, ca. 1950s-70s (Box 168, Folder 2020)
    - Postcards: MOMA artworks, n.d. (Box 168, Folder 2021)
    - Rothschild wine bottle labels, 1945-69 (Box 168, Folder 2022)
    - Stickers, n.d. (Box 168, Folder 2023)
    - Notecards, n.d. (Box 169)
    - Postcards: art, n.d. (Box 170)
    - Postcards: art, n.d. (Box 171)
    - Postcards: art & travel views and scenes (Box 172)
    - Postcards: travel views and scenes (Box 173)
    - Slides: artworks, n.d. (Box 174)
    - Slides: artworks (glass slides), n.d. (Box 175)
- Clippings, 1931-93; Series VII; 5.67; (14 boxes)
  Series VII, Clippings, is arranged alphabetically.
  - Architecture, 1947-87 (Box 176, Folder 2024-2026)
  - Art: exhibitions and acquisitions, 1941-85 (Box 176, Folder 2027-2033)
  - Art: exhibitions and acquisitions (Box 177, Folder 2034-2036)
  - Art: general, 1945-93 (Box 177, Folder 2037-2040)
  - Art: history, 1957-83 (Box 177, Folder 2041-2043)
  - Art: images, ca. 1941-83 (Box 178, Folder 2044-2049)
  - Art: MOMA, 1931-84 (Box 178, Folder 2050-2054)
  - Art: MOMA (Box 179, Folder 2055)
  - Art: People
    - "A", 1966-79 (Box 179, Folder 2056)
    - "B", 1954-85 (Box 179, Folder 2057-2058)
    - "C", 1936-83 (Box 179, Folder 2059-2060)
    - "D", 1951-84 (Box 179, Folder 2061)
    - "E", 1943-76 (Box 179, Folder 2062)
    - "F", 1967-84 (Box 179, Folder 2063)
    - "G", 1955-81 (Box 179, Folder 2064)
    - "H", 1963-80 (Box 179, Folder 2065)
    - "I", 1971 (Box 180, Folder 2066)
    - "J", 1966-84 (Box 180, Folder 2067)
    - "K", 1952-85 (Box 180, Folder 2068)
    - "L", 1959-77 (Box 180, Folder 2069)
    - "M", 1940-85 (Box 180, Folder 2070-2072)
    - "N", 1963-82 (Box 180, Folder 2073)
    - "O", 1963-86 (Box 180, Folder 2074)
    - "P", 1957-85 (Box 180, Folder 2075-2077)
    - "R", 1942-85 (Box 180, Folder 2078-2079)
    - "S", 1940-79 (Box 180, Folder 2080-2081)
    - "T", 1953-83 (Box 180, Folder 2082)
    - "U", 1959 (Box 180, Folder 2083)
    - "V", 1949-78 (Box 181, Folder 2084)
    - "W", 1963-84 (Box 181, Folder 2085)
    - "Z", 1967-80 (Box 181, Folder 2086)
    - Multiple people, 1943-81 (Box 181, Folder 2087-2089)
  - Athletes, 1943-56 (Box 181, Folder 2090)
  - Book reviews, 1940-90 (Box 181, Folder 2091-2096)
  - Book reviews (Box 182, Folder 2097-2102)
  - Books and typography, 1935-44 (Box 182, Folder 2103)
  - Commercial notices, 1950-83 (Box 182, Folder 2104-2105)
  - Current Events, 1940-86 (Box 183, Folder 2106-2111)
  - Dance and theater, 1946-85 (Box 183, Folder 2112-2117)
  - Essays and articles, 1954-85 (Box 184, Folder 2118-2121)
  - Film, 1952-86 (Box 184, Folder 2122)
  - Financial, 1959-84 (Box 184, Folder 2123)
  - Food and wine, 1964-86 (Box 184, Folder 2124)
  - Gardening, 1944-82 (Box 185, Folder 2125)
  - Health and fitness, 1958-84 (Box 185, Folder 2126)
  - Homosexuality, 1971-81 (Box 185, Folder 2127)
  - Literature, 1938-83 (Box 185, Folder 2128-2132)
  - Music, 1940-82 (Box 185, Folder 2133)
  - Natural Sciences, 1948-83 (Box 185, Folder 2134)
  - People
    - "A", 1942-84 (Box 185, Folder 2135)
    - "B", 1953-86 (Box 186, Folder 2136)
    - "C", 1956-86 (Box 186, Folder 2137-2139)
    - "D", 1973-87 (Box 186, Folder 2140)
    - "E", 1976 (Box 186, Folder 2141)
    - "F", 1963-85 (Box 186, Folder 2142)
    - "G", 1955-81 (Box 186, Folder 2143)
    - "H", 1946-81 (Box 186, Folder 2144)
    - "I", 1973-77 (Box 186, Folder 2145)
    - "J", 1978 (Box 186, Folder 2146)
    - "K", 1943-86 (Box 186, Folder 2147)
    - Kinsey, Alfred, 1953 (Box 186, Folder 2148-2149)
    - "L", 1959-79 (Box 186, Folder 2150)
    - Lynes, George Platt, 1981 (Box 186, Folder 2151)
    - "M", 1954-80 (Box 187, Folder 2152)
    - Maugham, Somerset, 1960-62 (Box 187, Folder 2153)
    - Moore, Marianne, 1945-87 (Box 187, Folder 2154)
    - "N", 1948-70 (Box 187, Folder 2155)
    - "O", 1946-85 (Box 187, Folder 2156)
    - "P", 1969-81 (Box 187, Folder 2157)
    - Porter, Katherine Anne, 1967-80 (Box 187, Folder 2158)
    - "R", 1960-85 (Box 187, Folder 2159)
    - Rockefeller Family, 1941-85 (Box 187, Folder 2160)
    - Rothschild Family, 1954-86 (Box 187, Folder 2161)
    - "S", 1961-84 (Box 187, Folder 2162)
    - "T", 1959-84 (Box 187, Folder 2163)
    - "U", n.d. (Box 187, Folder 2164)
    - "V", 1975-78 (Box 187, Folder 2165)
    - "W", 1943-88 (Box 187, Folder 2166)
    - "Y", n.d. (Box 187, Folder 2167)
    - Multiple people, 1961-83 (Box 187, Folder 2168)
  - Pornography, 1969-73 (Box 187, Folder 2169)
  - Quotations, comics, and jokes, 1965-85 (Box 187, Folder 2170)
  - Stamps, 1971-82 (Box 187, Folder 2171)
  - "To be sent" clippings, 1964-87 (Box 187, Folder 2172)
  - Travel, 1937-86 (Box 188, Folder 2173-2181)
  - Wescott family, 1935-77 (Box 188, Folder 2182)
  - Wescott, Glenway, 1939-87 (Box 188, Folder 2183)
  - Wheeler family, 1962, n.d. (Box 188, Folder 2184)
  - Wheeler, Monroe, 1936-58 (Box 188, Folder 2185-2187)
  - Wheeler, Monroe, 1960-88, n.d. (Box 189, Folder 2188-2191)
  - Wheeler, Monroe - Obituaries, 1988 Aug (Box 189, Folder 2192)
  - Notes accompanying clippings, n.d. (Box 189, Folder 2193)
- Health and Estate Materials, 1936-91; Series VIII; 3.15; (8 boxes)
  Series VIII, Health and Estate Materials, consists of two subseries, which are arranged alphabetically.
  - HEALTH
    - Appointments and prescriptions, ca. 1970s-80s (Box 190, Folder 2194)
    - Bills and receipts, 1974-88, n.d. (Box 190, Folder 2195-2201)
    - Health care information, ca. 1950s-80s (Box 190, Folder 2202)
    - Insurance certificates and cards, ca. 1939-66 (Box 190, Folder 2203)
    - Insurance claim forms, n.d. (Box 191, Folder 2204)
    - Insurance information from MOMA, 1988, n.d. (Box 191, Folder 2205)
    - Medical identification card, n.d. (Box 191, Folder 2206)
    - Medical notations for Eric J. Tomasello, 1979-81 (Box 191, Folder 2207)
    - Medical equipment rental information, 1988 (Box 191, Folder 2208)
  - ESTATE
    - Bills, financial statements, and receipts, 1976-91 (Box 192, Folder 2209-2218)
    - Account book, 1987-88 (Box 193, Folder 2219)
    - "Birthday Party: Remembering Glenway Wescott" by Jerry Rosco, printed version, The Northern Review, 1990 (Box 193, Folder 2220)
    - Cash journal for expenses during MW's trip to England, 1988 (Box 193, Folder 2221)
    - Check book, 1985-86 (Box 193, Folder 2222)
    - Checkbook register, 1987-88 (Box 193, Folder 2223)
    - Checkbook register, 1988 (Box 193, Folder 2224)
    - Checkbook register, 1988 (Box 194, Folder 2225)
    - Blank checks and deposit slips, ca. 1987-88 (Box 194, Folder 2226)
    - Correspondence
      - Letters from Hartman and Craven [law firm], 1988-91 (Box 194, Folder 2227)
      - Letters from Hunt and Faherty [law firm], 1987-88 (Box 194, Folder 2228)
      - Letters to and from Anatole Pohorilenko, 1987-91 (Box 194, Folder 2229)
    - Cremation receipts: MW, 1988 (Box 195, Folder 2230)
    - Death certificate: MW, 1988 Aug 17 (Box 195, Folder 2231)
    - Eulogies for GW by Jane Gunther and Felicia Geffen, 1987 Mar (Box 195, Folder 2232)
      with letter from Margaret M. Miller
    - Information re: household employees, 1988-89 (Box 195, Folder 2233)
    - Investment statements, 1986 (Box 195, Folder 2234)
    - Invitation to memorial service for GW, with response cards, 1987 Mar (Box 195, Folder 2235)
    - List of artworks pertaining to GW, 1987 (Box 195, Folder 2236)